Four people... Three minutes... Two choices... One chance for survival.
By Dawn's Early Light is a tv movie, action,
drama film directed by Jack Sholder.
A nuclear warhead launched by Soviet insurgents protesting the
waning Cold War destroys the Ukrainian city of Donetsk.
The destruction sets off a race between American and Soviet
politicians to prevent a nuclear holocaust.
While the U.S.
president feverishly works to keep the military and political machine
from going into overdrive, various subordinates panic.
When the president is believed to be killed in a
helicopter crash, zealous advisers take over.
Cassidy, played by Powers Boothe.
Moreau, played by Rebecca De Mornay.
Alice, played by James Earl Jones.
President, played by Martin Landau.
Condor, played by Darren McGavin.
Colonel Fargo, played by Rip Torn.
By Dawn's Early Light is an HBO original movie, first aired in 1990.
It is based on the 1983 novel Trinity's Child, written by William Prochnau.
The film explores themes of soviet union, bomber, nuclear
missile, north atlantic treaty organization (nato).
The tone is emotional and intense.